A tense car chase is continuing at the scene.
（テレビ音声:キャスター）
現場では緊迫した―
カーチェイスが続いています
That bastard...
（戸崎優(とさきゆう)）
あの野郎…！
（中野攻(なかのこう)）
永井！
こんな事しなくてもいいだろ！
Nagai! Are you sure we have to do this?
Out of the way, Nakano!
（永井圭(ながいけい)）
邪魔するな 中野！
And your job is?
（戸崎）
君の仕事は何だ？
To protect you.
（下村泉(しもむらいずみ)）
あなたを守ることです
I never wanted to see your face again.
（圭）
あなたの顔なんて
二度と見たくありませんでしたよ
Kill!
殺せっ！
Stop!
やめろっ！
I’m here to make a deal.
（圭）
ここへは取引をしに来た
You think I can trust an Ajin?
亜人など信用できるかっ！
We're taking down Satou even if it’s the last thing we do!
（攻）
俺たちは 何が何でも
佐藤を倒すつもりだ！
だから！
We'll become your pawns!
あんたの駒になってやるよ！
Your immortal soldiers!
（圭）
不死身の兵士として
We’ve apprehended the suspects.
（平沢(ひらさわ)）
容疑者は確保した
Was it Nagai Kei?
（警官）
永井圭でしたか？
No, it was someone else. It did look like him, though.
（平沢）
いや 別人だ　似てるだけのな
-Please support Ajin financially when it becomes available to you.-
So, we meet again. It's Satou.
（モニター画面:佐藤(さとう)）
やあ またまた会ったね　佐藤だ
As far as I know, the government has not responded to my demands.
（佐藤）
私の知る限り―
我々の要求に対する
政府からの返答はない
So, I’ve decided to get started.
（佐藤）
だから 始めることにした
Yes, it’s the young man who’s at the start of the batting list.
（佐藤）
そう トップバッターの
若井(わかい)さんだ
（若井のうめき声）
And with that...
そして これが…
（うめき声）
（銃声）
（机を叩く音）
（佐藤）
カウントダウン開始の合図だ
...I begin the countdown.
And as the second wave progresses,
we’ll start preparing for the third one.
（佐藤）
この第２ウエーブの
終了とともに―
（佐藤）
我々は次のウエーブへと駒を進める
And third wave will be the last.
第３ それが最終ウエーブだ
I will take over this country.
私が この国を統治する
（戸崎）
10分ほど前に―
This video was uploaded to Ajin.net 10 minutes ago.
“AJIN.net”に
アップロードされたものだ
The storm is coming.
嵐が来る
♪接近戦　切り裂く♪
♪僕の前に立っている
お前は誰だ？♪
♪逃げ続けるのも永遠じゃなくて♪
♪噛み砕き飲み込んだリアルに♪
♪Shout it out
そして曖昧さを断って♪
♪影の危うさを知りながら♪
♪ある種の冷静すぎるシステム♪
♪ON or OFF 今ならどっちだ？♪
♪結果　何度感情を殺して♪
♪いいえ　そもそもすり抜けて♪
♪壊されて　いっただけ♪
♪ほっといてくれ　Craze♪
♪僕は僕であって
切羽詰まったって♪
♪yeah yeah♪
♪最初からリスクだけのスタート♪
♪ぶっこんでいけ　Craze♪
♪むき出す本能　本性で♪
♪反転攻勢　yeah♪
♪切り裂いた　お前は誰だ？♪
Everyone around
here is an idiot.
（ゲン）
配分 間違えないでね
Make sure to mix it properly.
（高橋(たかはし)）
わーってるよ
I won’t mess it up!  You’re starting to sound like Okuyama.
お前 だんだん
奥山(おくやま)みてぇになってきたな
If you mess it up, the only consequence is that you’ll die.
失敗しても
死ぬだけだからいいけど
（高橋とゲンの笑い声）
（ゲン）
どう？　似てた？
Sounds just like him, that was great!
いいね いいね
Okay, all finished!
はい 完成
Wow, this is impressive.
（佐藤）
いやあ すごいね
Might even say that it's Oscar nomination worthy.
（佐藤）
オスカーに
ノミネートされてもいい出来だよ
[screen: flight ticket confirmation]
Here, give this to Satou.
（奥山(おくやま)）
はい これ
（奥山）
佐藤さんに渡しておいて
（田中功次(たなかこうじ)）
ちゃんと２席分取ったか？
Did you make sure to get two seats?
Yeah.
（奥山）
うん
I wonder if it’s really untraceable.
本当に足は
つかないんだろうな？
（ため息）
If you put that much care into your marksmanship, you'd get really good.
（奥山）
射撃でも
それくらい用心深くなれば―
うまくなるのに
Shut up.
うるせぇよ
I paid with a card under a stranger's name, so it's fine.
決済は 他人名義の
カードでしたから大丈夫
I used card info that I bought on a Russian site. They have a quite a few with Japanese names.
ロシアのサイトで買った
カード情報を―
タイプしたものだよ
（奥山）
日本人名義のも
結構 落ちてるんだ
ほぅ
And I use virtual currency to do business, so it can’t be traced.
（奥山）
それに 取引には
仮想通貨を使うから―
絶対に足はつかない
Oh?  The world changed a lot while I was away.
へぇ
しばらくいない間に―
とんでもねぇ
世の中になってんだな
With some effort, even a junior high school student could do it.
（奥山）
やろうと思えば
中学生でもできるよ
Tanaka-kun.
（佐藤）
田中君
Who are you?
誰だ？
On edge, as usual. It’s me.
（佐藤）
物騒だなぁ 私だよ
へ？
Satou-san, is that you?
佐藤さん… すか？
いい出来だろう？
Remarkable work, isn’t it?
（田中）
ホントに奥山で大丈夫すか？
Are you okay with Okuyama handling everything? I don't like his attitude.
あいつド下手っすよ
Ideally you'd be suitable, but your face is too well-known. I'm sure it's fine.
本来なら君が適任なんだけど―
顔割れ過ぎてるからね
ま 何とかなるよ
（♪）
（圭）うぅ…くっ…
Why do I... have to do this...
なんで 僕が… こんな事…
はぁっ…
I can't do any more.
もう 無理
まだ 20回もやってねぇぞ
You haven't even done twenty.
I’m from a white-collar background.
（圭）
僕はホワイトカラーなの
I know you're right for this job.
（平沢）
適材適所は認める
But you weigh 4 kilos more than our data from 40 days ago. You gotta lose it.
（平沢）
だが 40日前のデータより
４キロも増えてる
それだけは落とせ
I wonder if this is what corporate hell feels like.
ブラック企業ってこんな感じかな
Nagai Kei!
（戸崎）
永井圭！
しっかりやれ　サボるな！
Do it properly!  No slacking!
I should have killed you when I had the chance!
（圭）
あーあ！　殺しときゃよかったな！
I'll dunk you in a vat of formalin!
（戸崎）
ホルマリン漬けにするぞ！
（圭）
ちっ ひどいやつ
Can't believe him...
What?  Three more sets? That’s way more than Nagai!
（攻）
えーっ
あと３セットもやんのかよ！
それじゃ 永井の倍じゃねーか！
You're right for this job. You’re our muscle around here.
（平沢）
適材適所だ
お前は筋肉担当だからな
What? That sounds pretty idiotic.
はぁ？　なんか馬鹿みてぇじゃん
Don’t complain. If you finish, I’ll show you how to use the tranquilizer gun I mentioned earlier.
（真鍋(まなべ)）
まあ そう愚痴るな
さっき言ってた 麻酔銃の使い方も
教えてやるから
Really?  Don’t break your promise!
（攻）
ホントだな！？
ちゃんと約束守れよ！
（攻）
よっ！
（泉）
戸崎さん
Tosaki-san. I got word from Sokabe-san, it seems that in the end Sakurai-san isn’t going to change his plans.
曽我部(そかべ)さんから
連絡がありまして―
桜井(さくらい)氏は
やはり予定を変更しないそうです
Is that so? Good grief.
そうか
まったく こんな時に出張とはな
To take a business trip at a time like this... He really is careless.
のんきなものだ
He upped his bodyguards, and said that on the contrary,
once he reaches his destination, he’ll be safer.
警護も増員しましたし―
向こうに着いてしまえば
逆に安全だろうとのことでした
Well, then...
では
（戸崎）
下村君
Shimomura-kun. You should move here as soon as possible.
君も なるべく早く
住居を移してくれ
We need to focus on coming up with a plan for how to restrain Satou.
これから集中的に―
佐藤を拘束するための作戦を
考えなければならない
Understood.
分かりました
そのためには―
To do that, we need to clarify what we have that Satou doesn't.
我々にあって 佐藤にないものを
明確にしていく必要がある
This is our outpost.
ここが前哨基地だ
あぁ…
（圭）
ぶはーっ ふぅ
（攻）
そんなん飲んだら体重落ちねぇぞ
You’ll never lose weight drinking that.
Recovery from exhaustion calls for sugar content.
疲労回復には糖分が必要なんだよ
All you did was strength training.
筋トレやっただけじゃねぇか
Nagai-kun.  Nakano-kun.
永井君 中野君
（攻）
はっ！
あっ ああ…
Do you need something?
（圭）
何でしょうか？
I want you to meet someone.  Come with me.
（泉）
会わせたい人がいるの
ついて来て
Okay.
はい
あ？
何だ？　どうした 中野？
What is it? Is something wrong, Nakano?
下村さんて―
Shimomura-san is... really pretty, isn’t she.
すげぇ 奇麗だよな
Think she and Tosaki-san are going out? They’re always together.
トザキさんと デキてんのかな？
いつも一緒にいるし
I doubt that. I mean, she’s an Ajin.
それはないと思うぞ
だって あの人 亜人だろ
えっ！？
What?
You didn’t notice?
お前 気付いてないのかよ…
She brought out a ghost at the hospital.
病院で幽霊出してただろ
And when we were escaping from the village.
村から逃げる時にもいたし
彼氏いんのかなぁ
I wonder if she has a boyfriend.
あぁ…
What are you doing?
（泉）
何してるの？
Hurry up.
早くして
（ドアが開く音）
Oh?
（圭）
あ…
Who’s that?
誰？
Ogura...Ikuya! The American Ajin researcher!
オグラ･イクヤ
アメリカの亜人研究者だ
Genius.
（オグラ・イクヤ）
天才だよ
You’re Nagai Kei, correct? Japan’s third Ajin.
（オグラ）
君が永井圭だな
国内３例目の亜人
I’m Nakano.
俺は中野です
Ajin are interesting. They make you wonder if even the most meaningless of lives have value.
（オグラ）
亜人は面白い
無意味な人の一生にも―
価値があるのだと
ほのめかしてくれる
I’m uh, Nakano-
あの中野…
（オグラ）
吸ってもいいかな？
Mind if I smoke?
すみません
たばこは苦手なんです
Please don't. I can't stand the smoke.
（オグラが煙を吐く音）
（せき）
Nagai-kun. Why do you think people have to die?
（オグラ）
永井君
人は なぜ
死ななければならないと思う？
...Because their hearts stop?
心臓が止まるから？
細胞の再生回数には
限度があるからだ
Because there’s a limit to the number times that cells can regenerate.
それを超えると
再生が行われず―
Once you reach that, regeneration stops, and life ceases to functi...
生命としての機能が停止する
（オグラ）
違う
Wrong. It’s because that's how the universe decided it'd be.
宇宙がそう決めたからだ
（圭）はぁ？
（攻）あぁ？
Ogura-san. Save the small talk for later. Get on with the discussion.
（戸崎）
オグラさん 余談はいい
話を進めてくれ
According to Tazaki-kun behind that  camera-
（オグラ）
カメラの向こうの
タザキ君が言うには…
It’s Tosa-
トザ…
-your IBM is pretty unusual.
（オグラ）
君のＩＢＭはかなり変らしいな
It's Tosaki.
トサキだ
Bring it out.
出してみろ
（圭）え？
（攻）え！？
死ぬかもしれませんよ
You might die.
You sound like a pack of cigarettes.
たばこのパッケージか お前は
Is it really okay, Ogura-san?
（泉）
いいんですか？　オグラさん
No, it’s not!
駄目だって！
黙れ
Shut up. I can’t write a chart without seeing my patient first.
患者を診ずに カルテが書けるか
You won’t be able to see it, anyway.
（圭）
でも どうせ見えないでしょ？
殺す気で来い
Do it like you mean to kill me.  Then I’ll be able to see it.
それなら見える
（攻）
な…
Its shape is plain, but it’s very concentrated.
形状はプレーンだが
濃度が高いな
It’s unusual for it to be so well-defined.
ここまでクッキリ見えるのは
珍しい
I wonder if this is what corporate hell feels like.
（圭ＩＢＭ）
ブラック企業ってこんな感じかな
I need to pee.
（圭ＩＢＭ）おしっこしたい…
（圭）しゃべれ
Keep talking.
It’s just as reported. So it does exactly
the opposite of what you command?
（オグラ）
報告どおりだな
命令と逆の行動を取る… か
It seems its nature is twisted through and through.
とことん根性が
ねじ曲がってるらしい
（笑い声）
（攻）
がはっ…
ん… なんで 俺…
Why me?
（オグラ）
おまけに命令なしだと
オートランか
And it's self-propelled without orders. Very interesting.
こいつは面白い
（攻）
ああ はぁっ…
There was a similar case with an ajin farmer in Iowa.
アイオワの農家出身の亜人で
似たような事例があったな
At first, the IBM was allowed to do
simple farm work, like pulling up weeds.
（オグラ）
最初のうちはＩＢＭに―
草むしりなどの
単純作業をやらせていた
But one morning a few years later, it decided for itself
to start harvesting corn. It was even riding a tractor.
だが 数年後のある朝―
自発的に
コーンの刈り入れを始めた
トラクターに乗ってな
君の場合
長いこと ほっときすぎたな
In your case, you’ve left it alone for too long.
（圭）
え？　でも―
What? No, I first brought it out about a month ago.
１カ月前くらいですよ？
初めて出したのは
No, it’s been a lot longer for you. Probably since infancy.
（オグラ）
いや 君は もっと昔からだ
多分 幼少期
（攻）
あっ やばい！
Hey, watch out!
（泉）
ふぅ…
What should we do?
どうしましょうか？
Leave it there. It’ll disappear in five minutes.
ほっとけ ５分も経ちゃ消える
Huh?
え？
（オグラ）
何だ？
What?
Well, when I was trying stuff out before, I was
able to keep it out for as long as 30 minutes.
（圭）
いや 前にいろいろ調べた時は―
30分持ったこともありましたよ
How many times could you bring it out in a row?
連続で何体 出せた？
According to the report, five times.
（泉）
報告書に５体と記載しましたが…
My record is nine.
（圭）
最高記録は９体ですよ
ハハハ… 異常だ
That's odd. Your IBM is abnormally concentrated.
異常なくらい ＩＢＭが濃い
My ghost is... concentrated?
幽霊が… 濃い？
What’s with that amount?
何なんだ？　その量は
That’s true, Satou-san said the same thing.
確か 佐藤さんも
そんなこと言ってたな
Hey, Nagai! You got my shirt dirty!
（攻）
おい永井！　汚れたぞ！
Aren't you used to that, blue-collar boy?
ブルーカラーは慣れっこだろ？
赤だろ！
But this is red!
Aren't you used to that, blue-collar boy?
That kind of concentration is unthinkable without a suitably long period of time.
（オグラ）
相当な長期間でないと―
この濃度はあり得ない
No, this isn't just because of time.
いや 期間だけが要因じゃない
Variations occur depending on a person's ego
and stage of emotional development.
ＩＢＭの濃度は―
自我や心の発育段階によっても
変わってくる
君は いつから亜人なんだ？
How long have you been an Ajin?
え…？
Like I said, only for about a month.
だから １カ月前くらいですよ
Please wait a moment.
（係員）
少々 お待ちください
Thank you for waiting. Boarding
starts 30 minutes before the flight.
（係員）
お待たせしました
搭乗は30分前からとなります
Have a good trip.
良い旅をお過ごしください
I sure will.
（佐藤）
ああ ばっちり楽しんでくるよ
Ok, all clear.
（係員）
異常なし
Here... you are.
（奥山ＩＢＭ）
どう… ぞ
Good work.
お疲れ
You’re... wall...well...ca..come.
（奥山ＩＢＭ）
どう… イタ…
イテ… いたテまして
You’re dexterous, but you can’t get
the hang of controlling your IBM, can you.
君は器用なのに―
幽霊の扱いだけは
なかなか うまくならないねぇ
It doesn't work quite the... some... same as a machine.
（奥山ＩＢＭ）
機械みテには
イケ イカ ないね
Well, it’s just a matter of practice.
ま 何事も練習だよ
Simo Hayha?
（奥山ＩＢＭ）
シモ… ヘイヘ？
As I'd expect of Okyuama-kun. Well, I’ll be off.
さすが 奥山君だ
じゃ いってくるよ
（男性１）
宮古島は２日目だって
Day two is Miyako-jima. I wonder if they're'll be any cute girls?
（男性２）
可愛い子いるかな？
（男性３）
やばい… 緊張してきた
This is bad, I’m getting nervous.
Still?  I told you, it's fine. My dad's nice.
（女性）
もう？　大丈夫だって
お父さん優しいから
Do you think we need to worry about terrorism?
（男性４）
テロとか大丈夫すかね？
（男性５）
そんなこといいから
資料確認させてくれ
Forget about that, let me check the documents.
Now that you mention it, did you see the first-class
passengers? I wonder if it's a criminal escort.
（男性４）
そういえば ファーストクラスの客
見ました？
（男性４）
あれ 犯人護送とかすかね？
What?  There’s no way they would use first class for a criminal escort.
（男性５）
はぁ？
犯人護送にファーストクラス
使うわけないだろ
（桜井）
おどおどすんな
Don’t be so nervous.
They've checked every passenger on board. Isn’t that right?
客の身元チェックは済んでんだ
そうだな？
Yes sir.
（ＳＰ）
はい
Would they really follow me to Okinawa?
やつらも さすがに
沖縄までは追ってこんだろう
Well, if they do come, we’ll catch ‘em, and experiment on ‘em!
ま 来るなら来たで
とっ捕まえて 実験室行きだ
Hey! Sakurai-san!
（部下）
ちょっと 桜井さん
（笑い声）
We will be taking off momentarily.
（ＣＡ）
まもなく 離陸します
（飛行機が飛び立つ音）
（佐藤）
あ…
さて…
Well then.
（ＣＡ）
あ…
Sir, the seat-belt sign is still-
お客様
ベルト着用のサインがまだ…
Huh? Where’s Sakurai-san?
あれ？　桜井さんは？
（部下）
え…？
あの お客様
Excuse me, sir-
（銃声）
ひぃっ
（ＣＡの悲鳴）
（銃声）
（佐藤）
だぁっ…
ぐぁっ…
（銃声）
うっ…
（窓が割れる音）
（ＣＡの悲鳴）
あっ…
ど どうなってる！？
What’s going on?
あっ…
（機体がきしむ音）
Satou!
佐藤…
Oh, hello. So you were in the bathroom?
やあ　なんだ トイレだったのか
（銃声）
あら
（桜井）
はぁっ はぁっ…
ひぃっ ひぃっ…
（殴る音）
が… ご…
（桜井）どぁっ…
Bon voyage.
ボン･ボヤージュ
（爆発音）
So... I can create more IBMs than Satou and the others.
（圭）
僕は 佐藤さんたちより―
多くのＩＢＭを出せる… か
作戦に組み込めるかもな
I might be able to factor that into the plan.
君は いつから亜人なんだ？
How long have you been an Ajin?
（ドアを開ける音）
永井
Nagai.
はっ！
Freeze!
止まれっ！
（男たち）
おおっ
（攻）
あ… 大丈夫か？
Are you okay?
え？
Hey, Nagai!
（攻）
おい 永井！
（壁に押し付ける音）
Aren’t you acting a little strange?
They were just teaching me how to shoot!
ちょっと
おかしいんじゃねぇのか？
撃ち方 教わってただけだろ！
おかしいのは お前だ！
You’re the one who’s strange!
黒服との友達ごっこも
いい加減にしろ
Stop acting like those suits are your friends.
（攻）
はぁ？
Eh?
One of their skills is that they're capable of dying. It's something our side has that Satou's doesn’t.
あいつらのスキルのひとつは
“ちゃんと死ねる”ってことだ
これは 僕らにあって
佐藤にない
We may be able to use them as pawns
we can sacrifice as part of our plan.
捨て駒として
作戦に組み込めるかも
しれないんだ
ふ ふざけんな！
Watch your mouth! Are you telling me you've
never had anyone important to you in your life?
お前…
人を大切に思ったりとか
ねぇのかよ
I haven't.
（圭）
ない
Then what about that person they talked about on the news?
That friend of yours they said helped you escape?
（攻）
じゃあ ニュースで言ってた
“あの人”は？
お前の逃走を
手伝ってくれたっていう―
友達はどうなんだよ？
はっ！
I’m fine.
（海斗(かいと)）
俺は大丈夫だ
I’m on my way!
すぐ行く
We’re okay right now.
今は大丈夫だ
だって 友達だろ？
We’re friends, right?
Kei. You’re human.
圭！
お前は人間だよ
I don’t need him. Not anymore.
いらないよ もう
Spare emotions just make bad situations worse.
余分な感情は
状況を悪化させるだけだ
Clinging to them won't get you out of trouble.
情にすがったって
窮地は好転しない
Honestly, I’ve known it for a long time now.
本当は 昔から分かってたさ…
Let your heart guide you and your body will crumble.
心に流されれば 身を滅ぼす
Scum.
クズが！
馬鹿が
Idiot.
Have you seen Nagai and Nakano?
永井と中野を見なかったか？
After me.
来い！
（攻）
えっ？
I repeat.
（キャスター）
繰り返しお伝えします
Today at 3:25 p.m., flight TA16 from Haneda to Naha experienced problems,
（キャスター）
本日 午後３時25分―
羽田発 那覇空港行きの
ＴＡ１６７便が―
and made an emergency landing in the ocean off of Shizuoka Prefecture.
何らかのトラブルに
見舞われ―
静岡県沖に
不時着しました
According to our sources, we have information that Mr. Kazuo Sakurai,
関係者によると 亜人 佐藤の
殺害リストに記載されている―
who is on Satou’s assassination list, was on the plane.
桜井和夫(かずお)氏が乗っていたとの
情報もあり―
Police are considering the possibility of Satou's involvement, and are investi-
警察は 佐藤の関与の可能性も
視野に入れて…
だから 出張なんかやめとけと
言ったんだ
That’s why I told him to cancel his business trip.
That means-
では…
ああ 佐藤の仕業だ　間違いなくな
Yes. This is Satou’s work. No doubt about it.
ん…
（圭ＩＢＭ）
馬鹿が… いらないよ もう
Idiot.
I don’t need him... anymore.
しゃべれ
Keep talking.
（圭）
あの木を倒すな
Don’t cut down that tree.
Hey!
おい！
How annoying.
（圭ＩＢＭ）
うるさいな！
（圭）
うっ…
Kill!
殺せ！
Okay!
（圭ＩＢＭ）
はい
（圭）
うわっ！
馬鹿 やめろ！
Idiot! Stop it!
（圭ＩＢＭ）
黙ってろ！
ぐっ…
You!
こいつ…
You’re the one who’s strange.
（圭ＩＢＭ）
おかしいのはお前だ！
I’ve known that for a long time.
本当は 昔から分かってたさ
おかしいのはお前だ！
You’re the one who’s strange.
あーあ 殺しときゃよかったな
I should have killed you when I had the chance!
I should have killed you when I had the chance! I should have killed you when I had the chance!
殺しときゃよかったな！
Idiot. Idiot. Idiot. Idiot. Idiot! Idiot! Idiot! Idiot!!
（圭ＩＢＭ）
馬鹿が 馬鹿が 馬鹿が 馬鹿が
馬鹿が 馬鹿が 馬鹿が 馬鹿が！
Shut up.
くそ…
Everyone around here... is an idiot!
どいつもこいつも
馬鹿ばっかりだ
♪もう飽きたから交換しよう♪
♪お前が持ってる普通のと♪
♪キラキラしてる神のカードと♪
♪ザラザラしてる紙のカード♪
♪今度家に来たら♪
♪全部見せてやるよ♪
♪だから♪
♪校庭の隅に二人 風が吹いて♪
♪今なら言えるかな♪
♪誰にも言わない言葉♪
♪「優しくするから
遊びに来てよ」♪
♪「何でもあげるよ ねぇ」♪
♪「これからずっと
友達でいてよ」♪
Next episode
I’m always scared.